<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-08T19:54:01-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Bethany in the Taiga</title><subtitle>Bethany in the Taiga is a blog focuses on crafting, crochet, and cats!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Beginning Gingko Afghan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/crochet/ohmyblanket/afghan/christmasgifts/2018/10/04/ginkoafghan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beginning Gingko Afghan" /><published>2018-10-04T14:13:46-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-04T14:13:46-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/crochet/ohmyblanket/afghan/christmasgifts/2018/10/04/ginkoafghan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/crochet/ohmyblanket/afghan/christmasgifts/2018/10/04/ginkoafghan.html">&lt;p&gt;My mother loves arts and crafts style and I’ve always found the gingko motifs commonly found in the style to be exceptionally beautiful. While working on a “Oh My Blanket” for my own home, I noticed the similarities between the shell pattern and gingko patterns present in wallpaper and other textiles and decided to utilize a shell pattern for my mother’s Christmas afghan. Originally I attempted to try to create my own pattern to add stems to the leaves, but that did not work well and I stuck with the original Oh My Blanket pattern located here – https://www.mooglyblog.com/oh-my-blanket/ .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earthy watercolors and glazes are utilized in much of the art from the period and thought the new red heart supersaver ombre would be a good way to (economically) reflect that variation in colors. For this afghan I’m using redheart supersaver ombre’s “Candy Apple” and redheart supersaver solids “Cornmeal”. I’ve seen some really ornate handcrafted wooden frames used in arts and crafts pieces and I’m still trying to figure out the best way to reflect that in the border when I reach that point – i’m considering using a deep mahogany or claret colored border, possibly with some deep blue accents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I’m about a foot into the project and am really enjoying how the changes in green and yellow are crocheting up and I feel like intended style is really coming through.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My mother loves arts and crafts style and I’ve always found the gingko motifs commonly found in the style to be exceptionally beautiful. While working on a “Oh My Blanket” for my own home, I noticed the similarities between the shell pattern and gingko patterns present in wallpaper and other textiles and decided to utilize a shell pattern for my mother’s Christmas afghan. Originally I attempted to try to create my own pattern to add stems to the leaves, but that did not work well and I stuck with the original Oh My Blanket pattern located here – https://www.mooglyblog.com/oh-my-blanket/ .</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Completed Basketweave Afghan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/crochet/basketweave/afghan/christmasgifts/2018/09/25/afghancompletion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Completed Basketweave Afghan" /><published>2018-09-25T14:13:46-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-25T14:13:46-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/crochet/basketweave/afghan/christmasgifts/2018/09/25/afghancompletion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/crochet/basketweave/afghan/christmasgifts/2018/09/25/afghancompletion.html">&lt;p&gt;I finished the first of my Christmas gift crochet projects last evening – the Basketweave afghan for my
MIL! The border has been added and all the ends woven in, so it can get the official “complete” stamp! Overall, the project took approximately 2 1/2 weeks to complete which should allow me to stay on time for completion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the second time I’ve used this pattern and its a perfect pattern to do when watching TV or movies since its essentially all double crochet except for the small sections that create the weave effect. The previous version and pattern suggested three colors for the afghan, but I really like the way this one turned out with four colors. My MIL likes plaids and blues/browns and I think this afghan is going to fit in perfectly in her home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My very favorite border pattern is the spot on edging by attic24 which is what I used on this afghan. The instructions can be found here – http://attic24.typepad.com/weblog/spot-on-edging-2.html (though be aware that the instructions use British terms).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this is a new blog, I’m still working on formatting and such and have not had the chance to photograph the afghan yet. Pictures should be included by the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a lighter work schedule this week, so I am hoping to start working on my very first pattern inspired by art deco ginko leaves as well as finish up a quick shawl for myself. Fingers crossed that my idea for the ginko blanket works out and I’ll have more to share later this week!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I finished the first of my Christmas gift crochet projects last evening – the Basketweave afghan for my MIL! The border has been added and all the ends woven in, so it can get the official “complete” stamp! Overall, the project took approximately 2 1/2 weeks to complete which should allow me to stay on time for completion.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intro Post</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/crochet/crafts/intro/2018/09/21/intro-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intro Post" /><published>2018-09-21T16:07:46-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-21T16:07:46-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/crochet/crafts/intro/2018/09/21/intro-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/crochet/crafts/intro/2018/09/21/intro-post.html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the “Bethany in the Taiga” blog! Congratulations on finding your way to one of the odder corners of the internet! I’ve been knitting for nearly 13 years and crocheting for almost 7. After taking a several year break from the yarn arts due to an incredibly stressful job, I recently got back into crochet and now spend almost all of my free evenings working on afghans and other crocheted objects. My main motivation to start this blog came from a challenge to crochet or craft a gift for every person on my Christmas list and at least in the beginning, I hope to document that process here!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Welcome to the “Bethany in the Taiga” blog! Congratulations on finding your way to one of the odder corners of the internet! I’ve been knitting for nearly 13 years and crocheting for almost 7. After taking a several year break from the yarn arts due to an incredibly stressful job, I recently got back into crochet and now spend almost all of my free evenings working on afghans and other crocheted objects. My main motivation to start this blog came from a challenge to crochet or craft a gift for every person on my Christmas list and at least in the beginning, I hope to document that process here!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Basketweave Afghan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/crochet/basketweave/afghan/christmasgifts/2018/09/21/basketweaveafghan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basketweave Afghan" /><published>2018-09-21T14:13:46-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-21T14:13:46-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/crochet/basketweave/afghan/christmasgifts/2018/09/21/basketweaveafghan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/crochet/basketweave/afghan/christmasgifts/2018/09/21/basketweaveafghan.html">&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in my “intro” post, I’m currently working to craft a gift for everyone on my Christmas list. My current crochet project is a Basketweave Afghan for my mother-in-law. I previously completed another version of this same afghan as a housewarming gift for my aunt and though its not particularly my style, the DTRFP stitch makes it interesting to crochet. As of today, the afghan is about 75% complete and I’m hoping to finish it before going on vacation next week.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As I mentioned in my “intro” post, I’m currently working to craft a gift for everyone on my Christmas list. My current crochet project is a Basketweave Afghan for my mother-in-law. I previously completed another version of this same afghan as a housewarming gift for my aunt and though its not particularly my style, the DTRFP stitch makes it interesting to crochet. As of today, the afghan is about 75% complete and I’m hoping to finish it before going on vacation next week.</summary></entry></feed>